Expanding my plans

Day 01121: Sunday, 2018 April 01

Minetest log

I'd been trying to avoid defining the same bonus ability for two items that share an element so there's a difference to each possible deck configuration, though I'd been allowing reuse of bonus abilities between items that are mutually exclusive in their elemental ties. It just occurred to me though that all tools have wooden handles. Each tool, even tools of the same type, needs a different bonus ability, now that support for multiple element affinities in a single item is supported. This is going to be a pain. I think I'm going to try for unique abilities all around though, which is even more of a pain. I guess this proof-of-concept release will let me gage how much interest there is in this sort of thing. Am I the only person that wants this? Probably, but we'll see. At least I don't have to define all the item bonuses at once.

Visit

I visited with my mother for most of the non-work portion of my day. I'll go back tomorrow, too. It seems her iPhone's been doing ridiculous things, taking seconds-long videos every time she tells it to take a basic photograph. She sometimes remembers to specifically tell it not to do that, but it deletes that setting each time she goes to take a new photo. I thought it was because the developers at Apple are trying to push this seconds-long video feature that they're for some reason proud of, and they don't care that many people are (I'd assume) bothered by it. She pointed to a much more-likely cause though: Apple's been trying to rent her iCloud storage space. This stupid feature that she doesn't even want, and I'm not sure who would, it probably turning itself on to use up all her local storage space so she'll rent cloud storage space and make the company even more. I think I figured out how to disable it for good though. I'm not sure why the developers added that option, even though they did hide it. Maybe to seem less devious? Anyway, I tried to back her photos up to her desktop machine today for her, but her pocket computer and desktop computer stopped speaking to each other after a while. Hopefully they'll be working again tomorrow so I can finish the job.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Sick of reCAPTCHA and Google

Day 01122: Monday, 2018 April 02

Google's reCAPTCHA

I'm getting sick and tired of Google's new attitude in regards to reCAPTCHA. They've been refusing to let me access several sites that use the service for hours on end, as they refuse to even send the CAPTCHA to fill out. Bandcamp unfortunately uses their service on their log in page, and I've finally written to their support team via their Web form:

Over the past few months, I've been usually unable to log into my Bandcamp account. The problem is reCAPTCHA. Google's reCAPTCHA has been refusing to send CAPTCHAs to connections it thinks are automated, which make *ZERO* sense, as the CAPTCHAs are there to allow users to prove the connection *isn't* automated. I thought this would clear up on its own, but it hasn't. It's been taking me *hours* to get logged in and access my music, which has been frustrating enough, but also, an artist I listen to recently took one of their new albums down rather quickly. I managed to buy the album before it disappeared *this* time, but what about next? If I can't log in right away, I could miss things like this.

Could you please do something about this? If Google's reCAPTCHA isn't functional any more, maybe it's time to replace it as the CAPTCHA provider.

(I can send a screenshot of Google's error message on your site of you like, just let me know where to send it.)

Attempted visit

I ended up leaving the apartment late, so I showed up at my mother's place twenty minutes behind schedule. She didn't appear to be around, so at first I thought she'd given up waiting for me. But then, I realised that Vanessa has school today. My mother *almost never* answers the doorbell, so if Vanessa isn't around, visits don't succeed. I ended up coming back with a key, but it turned out my mother left the door unlocked in anticipation of my arrival.

Minetest log

I fixed the sand and desert sand renewal in renew, and finally made coral spawn rarely on shallow, underwater sand after long periods of time. Now, even if all coral is mined away, it'll eventually come back. I messed up the ABM for that at first though, making it spawn new coral with too high a probability. Furthermore, it seems that Minetest sets off all the ABMs as soon as you start the game; it's only after that that the timer starts setting them off. As a result of these two issues, one my own error and one a strange quirk in the game I had no reason to even consider existed, the central island has become home to a growing reef. I'm debating about whether I should remove it or let it continue growing. It's odd to have it there; it's a snow-laden, arctic region surrounded by tropical coral. Still, it'd be nice to have a local coral source.

I'm debating about how easy I want warp points to be to acquire. If only one set of warp points can be held at a time, I don't want them necessarily tied to one of the same stats as a drop-modifier, as there's no way to swap the warp point ability out temporarily without losing all warp points, such as for when mining particular items. That means I can't attach the ability to the wooden door, as it's powered by any sapling, each of which has a drop-modifier as an option using the same type of sapling as both the element and the deck item. It might be good to go back to the initial plan of using the steel door. This would have two major characteristics to account for. First, warp points would be easy to acquire. I don't know whether that's good of bad. Second ... Oh wait, never mind. I was thinking that would make the warp points mutually exclusive to the extra storage provided by having a locked chest in the deck, but the locked chest is also compatible with any sapling element. I was thinking that was good, as you'd have to choose between being able to jump around the map and being able to tote more with you. Still though, most people don't dig leaves for saplings often. It'd be an extra effort to use warp points and still have substantial extra storage space, which is a positive aspect of that configuration. On the other hand, obsidian doors provide the quality of rarity in warp points. Again, I don't know if that's good or bad. However, this would also has the issue that obsidian doesn't have many forms. I can't make one of them incredibly useful, as it'd be too easy of a choice which to use. I figure a select few bonus abilities will end up being great. This isn't by choice, but because of the sheer number of them. So far, I've only come up with about three that I think stand out among the others, so if I only accepted awesome ideas, this mod pack would flop and fail for the fifth time. Even in the original draft, it was never my intention that every bonus ability be the most useful feature ever. In fact, the original ability granted by corral was called "Corrals' Revenge" (the original draft involved displayed ability names) and would *reduce your health* when used, with the reduction increasing as you mine more and more coral. And finally, there's the option of the glass door. The new sand-renewal mechanics bring a whole heap of new items into the list of what I can support, so I haven't given much thought to what sand bonuses can do yet. Desert stone, grey stone bricks, et cetera ... I'll need to come up with some ideas before I can better understand the implications of using the glass door for this particularly potent ability.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

reCAPTCHA issues

Day 01123: Tuesday, 2018 April 03

Bandcamp account issues

Bandcamp support got back to me saying no one else has complained of the reCAPTCHA problem since they set their CAPTCHAs to be "invisible", and asked me to confirm my Web browser and operating system details that they had, probably from the User-Agent string I used when I filed for help. My response:

Hey Bryan,

Yeah, it's Firefox 45.9.0. It's the long-term support release of it, or whatever they're calling it; the one that gets bug patches but doesn't get all the new features right away. As you said, I'm also on Linux, specifically Debian 9.

I've attached a screenshot of the error message to this letter.

The "invisible" CAPTCHA hasn't been very invisible on my end. I've pretty much always had to click the CAPTCHA images, I've just had to do it after having submitting my log in details instead of before. Except over the past few months, reCAPTCHA has usually not been giving me the chance.

It's great to hear purchases will still work when logged out. Is there a way to access past purchases as well?

It's worth noting (for use in trying to explain why you don't see the problem on your end) that since before I registered a Bandcamp account, I've been a Tor user. I've put a lot of money into this account though; I'm a legitimate user, I just don't like middlemen eavesdropping on my connections. And last time I expressed issues with the website blocking me, you (or someone else on support) said you have no intent of blocking us Tor users. However, Google (and thus reCAPTCHA) is a different story. Google doesn't like us Tor users because Google makes its money not in legitimate sales like you do, but in selling the data of users to its advertisers. Google doesn't exactly like Tor users, and hasn't for a while. My guess is that this is yet another step they're taking to try to discourage the privacy that hurts their bottom line.

Thank you,
~ Alex Yst

Coupon ad registration

Yesterday, my mother pointed me toward a coupon-mailing list for Harbor Freight, a hardware store near Bi-Mart. Apparently, they offer "gratis" items frequently. To get them, you have to make a purchase, but you can buy anything in the store ant it will count. There's no minimum price requirement or anything like that. I'm right in that parking lot every week for my B-Mart trip, so it'd be a waste not to give their coupon mailer a try. Being Tuesday, I stopped by to sign up today. They wouldn't sign me up without a telephone number, even asking if I had a friend whose number I could give them since I don't have one. I don't know any numbers offhand, and even if I did, I wouldn't give them one for a couple reasons. First, I don't intend to buy into any company's ridiculous you-must-have-a-telephone system. By doing so, I'd be helping perpetuate the problem. But also, it wouldn't be my number to hand out. It'd be wrong for me to sign up for something using someone else's contact information without talking to them about it first. I said if a telephone number was required, I'd just have to give up, said my goodbye, and started walking away. That got them to be more reasonable; they called me back and input a fake telephone number: 541 555 5555. They must've thought that was an unused number because of the "###555####" format, but fun fact: Fake numbers within the +1 country code are in the format "###55501##" format. The number they used was very likely someone else's number! Not my problem though; I didn't choose that number. I noticed on the form too that it asked for the registrants gender, so I kept an eye on that field to catch them when they tried to misgender me. They didn't though. They just left that field blank when they submitted it, which I appreciate. There's no need to specify a gender for a coupon mailing list, seriously. Why was that field even included?

Lucky number drawing

The lucky ending digit for the week is five. I've got more than enough data by now, I just need to find the time to go back through my journal to compile it. It's be easier if I hadn't had to redact all my entries as of late.

Visit

I spent most of my day today with my mother, as I'll also do tomorrow. I haven't visited her at all this past term, as I was struggling to keep my sanity and keep on top of the workload, between the stress the school puts me under and the noxious nature of that English course. (The maths course was mostly okay.) After tomorrow though, I'm taking a week to myself before school is back in session; I desperately need it.

We went on her daily treasure hunt, and later, we went with Vanessa to get tacos. I've never had tacos with potato on them, but they were pretty good. We also sat and watched one of her television shows, which I pretended to enjoy. It's odd; I used to *actually* enjoy that particular show, long before she ever did, but I've changed so much. The mere fact that it's proprietary is enough to turn me off to it now. I guess it helps too that I have something better to do than watch television now too: program Minetest mods. I'm never going to finish the minequest project before school starts, but I'd love to have a good chunk of it done.

Vanessa's been having trouble getting her Bluetooth headset to function with her laptop. I thought she was on Debian, so I thought I could help, but she's switched to Mint on me. I tried, but got nowhere. It doesn't help that I've never used Bluetooth for anything myself. I ended up giving up and asking in the Linux Mint support IRC channel, where a couple knowledgable people helped me get it working. It seems there's a setting to toggle, it's easiest to toggle via an interface that isn't installed by default, and the setting resets itself upon reboot. I showed her how to reach the setting though, as well as how to reach volunteer tech support when I'm not nearby to assist. Unfortunately though, it seems the headset isn't much good to her. The connection works fine, but the microphone (the part she needed most) isn't very high in quality, so she can't be heard very well.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Strange data loss

Day 01124: Wednesday, 2018 April 04

Drudgery

I finally set about filing my taxes today. I started working with the same service I used last year, but they wanted to charge me for my state return this time, so I looked for another state tax-filing option. I found the link to get the service I used to file a state return gratis, but as I'd already given them my information this year, they refused to let me use the gratis option after finding it.

I found another service, which seemed better than most at first. They requested three telephone numbers: a main number, a mobile number, and a foreign number, but they also had a check box to indicate that you have no valid US number. However, upon checking that and submitting the form, they demand a mobile number; but they also add a new check box for indicating you have none. Upon submitting *that* form though, they demand a foreign number. As long as you tell them you have no US number, there's no way to get out of giving them a foreign number. I don't have time for this scrap though, and they didn't allow phrases such as "no telephone service", so I just told them my number is 0. Let's just see them try to call that and reach the operator or something.

Anyway, my taxes have been filed now, but I need to remember next year not to follow the links my tax preparer sends me. Instead, I need to reach their website through the link provided by my state's website.

Minetest log

Over the past several days, I've been testing new code but never mining. The tropical coral reef is really taking over my arctic island. I don't really have a way to keep the coral out of the arctic, but I do need to add some more limiters to the coral spread. I've made coral not generate too far from sand, to start with. That'll keep it from continuing to spread out as a layer across the ocean like it's been threatening to do. I've also made it spread slower. I won't be able to really see the effects of the new code though until I totally wreck the reef in about eight days. I'll clear out all the coral, just so I'll see when the new coral starts to grow and how fast it spreads.

I have no idea what happened, but everything in my world mods directory disappeared on me. It doesn't seem to exist on my filesystem any more. Included here was the unreleased yellow mod. No copies of this exist, so the mod is just gone now. An unreleased custom interface mod was here as well. My only local copies of blockprotectnodes, minestats, and minestats_sfinv were here, but I have copies in remote repositories. The only existing copies of arborist, antifire and drop_hack were here, but I can rebuild those. It'll be a slight pain, but I can do it. I don't recall what else was there. The biggest loss was everything minequest-related. Thankfully, minequest proper's only irreplaceable file was open in Geany at the time; I've saved it elsewhere, preserving its contents. yellow was lost in its entirety. I poured so much into that mod ... I guess it's true that I'd decided to go in a different direction and not use that mod in my own world, but I hadn't entirely written its replacement yet and I hadn't broken dependence on it yet. I was also considering actually releasing it, though not quite yet.

Unsatisfied, I tried to replicate the issue. All I'd used were Git and Minetest, and I was sure Git hadn't done this. Either Minetest had done this, or something on my system had had a freak malfunction that just happened to affect one of the main directories I was working with at the time. I have terrible luck, but even *my* luck's not usually *that* bad, at least not with such precision. I mean, I could loose the entire drive, but I wouldn't lose only this directory. I managed to work out the steps to repeat the problem, and in doing so, I found the cause. It seems Minetest deletes the contents of symlinked directories instead of the symlink itself, for symlinks in the world directories of worlds that get deleted. I'd been using symlinks to an outer directory to avoid losing my mods when removing a world, and instead, that *caused* the mods to be lost. I've now filed a bug report.

I was struggling to remember what all was in that directory; what all was lost. For piece of mind, I needed to figure out what mods weren't lost, which ones were lost and didn't matter, and which would need to be rebuilt. I racked my brain, but couldn't be sure I'd remembered everything. By the time my visit with my mother today concluded though, I'd realised how I actually needed to look at that directory. That directory housed the mods used in my main world; in other words, the mods I actually care about. (All mods I don't really use were spared.) These could be broken down into three categories: mods that were complete, mods that were incomplete, and mods that were there for legacy reasons and would be removed once I'd completed a replacement for them. Completed mods were released; I already cloned them back to my machine from the Internet before I left home. The main incomplete mods were the contents of the Minequest Modpack; I'd savaged the parts of that that were most important. All I need to do is think about what was incomplete but planned to belong in my world and what was was obsolete in my world but not yet replaced. This was a much simpler thing to try to come up with.

I think what I've lost (aside from some little things in the Minequest Modpack is just yellow, antifire, drop_hack, and arborist. drop_hack needs to have it's minequest equivalent programmed before the term begins. This is not optional, so I need to turn my focus to that now. arborist's functionality would be nice to have programmed into the Minequest Modpack, but it can wait a bit. yellow's replacement is all but complete. I need to clean up the code a bit, but more importantly, I need to decide upon which item will bear this ability when placed in the deck. antifire ... won't be urgent until I'm about to make the world public. Plus it needed some cleanup as far as implementation. And it needed to be renamed, as the name antifire turned out after I'd named the mod to be taken by another mod already, one that's been around much longer than mine. Don't get me wrong, the loss of yellow was killer. However, I think it was the only thing of real value that I *did* lose. I need to focus in a different area to recover now, but it's an area I'd focus in eventually anyway. Oh. Yeah. I also lost 10, which was responsible for the functionality of my custom, world-specific HUD. It'll be a pain to reprogram, but I can recover most of the code from the minestats_hud mod.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Clog

Day 01125: Thursday, 2018 April 05

Minetest log

The effects of drop_hack have now been implemented in the Minequest Modpack.

With how the developer I spoke with on IRC was talking yesterday, it sounded like my bug report might not be taken seriously. It seemed that they believed there wasn't cause for symlinks to be used in world directories, so the behaviour of using them there was undefined. I got what I got, but there was no reason to fix the code to avoid other people having the same happen to them. However, this morning, I found two developers had joined the conversation on the bug report page, excluding one that simply marked it as a bug and categorised it. The first called out the lead developer, saying they'd discussed this with them before. It's a *known* bug (though probably a forgotten bug)! The next found the exact cause of the bug and labelled the bug as high priority. There's a known fix, and it sounds relatively simple! I'd probably write up the patch myself if I had any clue what I'm doing in C++. I'm maintaining hope that this'll be repaired by the next stable release, though I'm not sure when that would be.

I'd hoped not to restart the world again, but between the revised mechanics of renew and the development of minequest, I think I'm going to anyway. The better renew mechanics mean that stone isn't the only material I can acquire in large quantities while building the tunnel, provided I have a steady source of tools to wear out as I go. I've already started building up the walls of the tunnel in stone though. I've got to tear all that out anyway. I think I've figured out how to reduce tool wear in minequest, so I should be able to drag out my tool usage for a while, and once I've made enough progress, I shouldn't need to wear out tools at all any more. Starting over will also clean out the database of the newly-bogus key/value pairs. The tracking of drops without a player is getting in the way of minequest development, so I'm removing it. Besides, that tracking was added to try to deal with other issues in Minetest Game that I've since fixed in renew. Tracking unclaimed drops was always beyond the scope of minestats, and should never have been added.

IRA issues

Today, the person in charge of out franchise dropped by the store, so I talked to them about the issues I've been having with the IRA people. It turns out the IRA people lied to me. They don't have any of my money at all, as the franchise owner hasn't done what needs to be done to allow the person in charge to set up the sending of money to the IRA people. Anyway, they said they'd make sure the IRA people had my propper informarion, because they think that's the problem. I don' think it is though, I think their website is just broken, and since they refuse to provide any support, I can't work around the problem. I got them to promise not to send the IRA people any of my money if they're ever able to get the system set up, just in case. I'm tired of dealing with these IRA people that won't even support their own service and deal with the problems they set up themselves in their Web interface.

Drain clog

My shower drain's been clogged for a while, but I haven't had time to do anything about it. Usually, I use this plastic snake thing to clear out hair, and everything returns to normal, but that didn't work this time. I figured a plunger might do better, but I needed to find time to look for an inexpensive, used one. However ...

My mother's water heater's gone out. Showering has gotten terrible at her place; it's just way too cold. I figured I'd clean out my shower a bit, then tell her to go ahead and use mine if she liked. It turned out she didn't need the invitation. Before I could get things set up, she invited herself to use it. No problems there; I don't mind at all. Anyway, being in a hurry now because of her lack of hot water at her place, I splurged and bought a brand new plunger. The store was out of the cheap ones, so I had to pay double the price to get one of the next level up. It didn't help though. At all. In fact, I think it might've made the clog somehow worse. The tub didn't seem to visibly drain at all, though I suspect it was just draining even more slowly than before.

I wrote to my mother to warn her of the problem. She could use my shower all she like, but she'd have water at her feet as she did so. She wouldn't leave well enough alone though. She couldn't just be satisfied to have access to warm water. Instead, she insisted I get the manager to come in and fix it. First of all, ignoring who the manager even is, I don't want to go get someone else to unclog my drain for me. However, the manager's been really nice and helped me get furniture and whatnot. I don't feel right sticking them with my clogged drain. My mother doesn't respond well to being told "no" though. It doesn't matter how unsolicited her advice is, she acts like you kicked her in the teeth if yo don't follow it to the letter.

At first, I figured I'd ignore her message. If she asked, I'd say I didn't respond specifically because I wasn't going with her plan but that she freaks out if told things like that. That wouldn't go over well. Then I decided to simply claim the message didn't come through. Too dishonest though. After a while, I wrote back with an excuse she couldn't really deny, but was completely bogus none the less. She'd know I wasn't getting the manager, but since she can't handle the truth, she wouldn't be getting that. I figured I'd go back to the store tonight and look for a different kind of snake, but before I went out, I filled the bathtub. I figured letting the weight of all the water press down on the clog while I was away might shove it through; sort of like how double-filling the toilet bowl forces lesser clogs though. I couldn't just let it be though. I had to try the plunger with all that water in there before heading out. I noticed this time though that water would spurt out from behind the drain-stopper switch plate as I plunged. There was a passage from behind that plate to the drain, so perhaps I could attack the clog with my current snake from this other angle. I started removing the plate, but before I could finish, the water started visibly and audibly draining. As I continued, the flow sped up. When I pulled the stopper out by the switch that operated it, the drain cleared completely. The stopper must sit partly-blocking the drain, even when toggled to not block the flow. Removing it entirely must've widened to passage enough to let the clog get washed away. I'm completely at a loss as to what could've been blocking my drain though if not the usual hair.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Setting minequest's initial goals lower

Day 01127: Saturday, 2018 April 07

Minetest log

I'd like to get the new world started, but I don't want to do that before getting the anti-tool-wear bonus programmed, even though I won't have access to it for a while anyway. My current plan with tool-based bonus abilities though had been to have the material of the tool determine the ability and the type of tool determine which group of nodes triggers it. That meant that before I can program any of the tool bonuses, I needed to know what all the bonuses will be; that way, I can attach each bonus to the most-fitting material. And of course, I'd decided to make the anti-tool-wear mechanic one of these tool-based bonuses. While I think reversed tool wear will be underappreciated, it's one of the most powerful abilities the Minequest Modpack will have to offer. Splitting it up so it only functions when digging certain nodes like this helps balance it out somewhat. Anyway, I was three ideas away from having the full set of six tool bonuses, if you don't count the bonuses for hoes and the screwdriver. Those tools behave very differently though, so the bonuses I'd want for them are mutually exclusive to the ones I'm trying to come up with now. I can deal with the hoes and screwdriver later, and in fact, I do already have a couple ideas for the screwdriver, including a screwdriver-specific anti-wear mechanic, seeing as anti-wear mechanics have to be context-specific or I can't get information on which player is causing the wear.

I worked myself up too much over the tool bonuses though, to the point where I had a strange dream about them. I don't remember the details, but it was weird. I'm giving up. For now. I'm dropping support for the newer tools from the proof-of-concept build, and going back to only supporting items from that initial, pre-0.4.0 version of the subgame. I'm dropping support for items in which the countable drop isn't yet available in the subgame version my respective beta builds are based on, postponing support for several items. Furthermore, I'm leaving support out for all items that are supportable only with renew until all the regularly-supportable items have been completed, and I'm pushing several items on my to-support list back to not be supported until later versions; not only from this initial version, but several other incremental versions as well. I'm down to on;y thirty-two items that will be supported in the proof-of-concept build. Of these, there are four tool materials, but the mese pick is strange in that it's the only tool in the mese set; there is no mese shovel, axe, or sword in older versions of the subgame. (It's worth noting that mese isn't countable in this pre-0.4.0 version of the game, but the wooden handle makes this still an item that can be attached to a countable, in this case, saplings.) Because the mese pick isn't part of a set (yet), I'm probably going to give it a bonus unlike the other tools, one that likewise isn't part of a set. With the to-support pool dropped so much, I don't think I want to start the world until I can at least finish support for these thirty-two items.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Creative block

Day 01128: Sunday, 2018 April 08

Minetest log

I wasn't thrilled yesterday to need to make the decision not to support elements added by renew in the Minequest Modpack until the very last phase of beta development. I didn't feel I had another choice at the time, but I knew it'd result in renew-defined elements being treated as second-class elements. And to be truthful, they are. Of the few people that will use minequest and the Minequest Modpack, I'm guessing very few to none will also install renew. renew simply isn't a popular mod, and I doubt minequest or the Minequest Modpack will see many fans either. However, minequest isn't for others. It's for me. I will be *ecstatic* if it gets popular, but I shouldn't allow how I assume others will perceive the Minequest Modpack to hold me back in getting what I want from it, and I should take special steps to ensure I give my self-defined elements the chance they deserve, as that'll make the modpack more enjoyable for me (especially in the beta versions, as full support is planned for everything eventually anyway).

My previous algorithm for determining what subset of items to support for the time being was terrible at best. It was the result of continuous changes in my plans mutating an initial, simple algorithm. Just how bad the algorithm was could be seen in how much had to be done by hand and how I either had to guess at some things or go back and try to review old Minetest Game version code that I have no intent of touching again once I've moved on to the next stage of support. I've coded up something much more reliable that only needs me to manually handle the data to figure out semantic stuff that the game will never be able to understand on its own. I've also worked support for renew in, so I can slowly add support for the renew elements as I slowly add support for the Minetest Game elements. I'm *much* happier with this result. Planned support for the proof-of-concept release is now up to forty-four items and four elements.

I've also decided to let go a bit more and allow items to take on bonuses I don't necessarily want them to, at least during the beta stages of development. I previously wanted the wooden door not to be the one to hold the warp point ability, but I've only come up with one door-related innate item ability so far. Why not let the wooden door use it during the proof-of-concept stage? It's not finalised, it's known to be highly unstable, and it's alright for me to make drastic, world-breaking changes at this point. (It's worth noting though that I've reconsidered my position on the wooden door being the warper; it might be a good idea *precisely* for the reason I didn't want it to happen.)

I've still hit a creative block though. I'm not sure what to add to the modpack. Still, this is the furthest I've come in all my iterations of minequest. I've never gotten beyond the stage where I implement the basic interface; I've never implemented the innate abilities for a player to draw out of even one item until this time. I'll be ecstatic if I can get this first proof-of-concept build released, even if I fail to take the project further than that. However, I think maybe other Minetest players would have ideas they'd volunteer if I can just get *something* released. I can't just release now with what I have though; I need more substantial work done on the specific abilities. Don't get me wrong. I've put a great amount of effort into the general code of the minequest core and the idea itself has been refined to the point that it's pretty solid now. It just ... lacks a "wow" factor. It doesn't flash. It doesn't sparkle. It'll get ignored without something more to show what its capable of. I haven't finished coding my current ideas though, so maybe by the time I do, I'll have some more to add.

onioncat

I stayed up pretty late last night and into the morning working on minequest, but I had some stuff I really wanted to get implemented before I turned in for the night. A friend came to me online though really excited about onioncat. It seems like a great tool for certain situations, but as I told them, it doesn't fit my use case. Annoyingly, they insisted on ignoring the fact that I was tired, the fact that I was busy, and the fact that I didn't have a use for it. I'd expressed an active disinterest in using it, but they insisted I stay up far later than even I'd planned to, not get what I wanted done done, and get onioncat installed and configured on my machine.

So, we spent the next few hours setting that up. In the end, I think we had it working, at which point I asked them what they'd wanted me to do with it. Apparently, they wanted me to just mess around with it. I was exhausted before we'd even started though. I explained that I could follow basic instructions in such exhaustion, but I couldn't just mess around with a completely-foreign piece of software. In my weary state, I just didn't have the brainpower! They laughed. They'd kept me up late setting up software I didn't even want and I didn't even have a purpose for, they didn't even have anything they wanted done with it, and all they did was laugh. No apology or anything. I need to try to remember not to fall for that garbage again. They're a great person, but they let their excitement get the better of them and pushed it onto me at a time I wasn't ready to deal with it. Next time, if I remember, I'll tell them to wait until morning, or a day off, or something.

Today saw the brief return of //quystystxtvdgyst.onion., which we used to give onioncat access to the Tor network. Or something. I'm not even clear on what we did. This wasn't even a learning experience for me, as I was way too tired to take in any new information. Anyway, with nothing to do once we reached what I guess was our destination, I shut the onion down again and put it back in cold storage. onioncat will probably continue running until next reboot though; I didn't shut that down. I doubt it'll come back online on its own after rebooting, but I'm not interested enough to look into it; not after the grief I've already had with it (through no fault of its own).

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Found a bug without even looking at the code or seeing it in action

Day 01129: Monday, 2018 April 09

A red Red Hat hat

A customer came in near the end of the night wearing a red hat bearing the Red Hat name and logo. I got excited to run into another Linux user, but it turns out the wearer didn't even know what they were wearing. They'd found the hat outside on the ground and thought it referred to as they put it,"some women's thing. I'm guessing they were talking about the Red Hat Society. There's no mistaking that logo though. It was definitely referring to the operating system.

Minetest log

I was trying to figure out how to provide post-count drop modifications in a minequest-related mod, when I realised that the inability to do it cleanly could be traced directly back to the underlying minestats counter. Perhaps I should add a new callback? Or extend the existing callback? I could require registered callbacks using the register_update_function() function to return a drop table, which would replace the original drop table. It'd be overhead though, and most registered update functions won't need the capacity. Still, this would be the cleanest way to achieve my current goal ...

After mulling it over a while though, I remembered that Lua tables are passed by reference. An update callback can simply modify the drop table passed to it and the modification should take effect! That means I introduced a bug last time I modified the code around that, which I think was yesterday. I figured I'd test when I got home to see if it behaved as expected, and if so, I'd document it and relabel it as a feature. If I was wrong and the bug hadn't been introduced, it'd be because of the order in which things were processed; I'd just rearrange the code a bit to introduce the capacity as a new feature. Literally, not a single character would likely need to be added or removed, just moved. The test showed the bug was in fact present though, so I started trying to make use of it.

As I looked at some code I needed to clean up to make use of this, before I could change a thing, I realised that this wouldn't work the way I'd planned. The particular issue I'm dealing with is that I've added an ability to sometimes automatically smelt the items you mine, but once the item's been smelted, it's not the countable drop any more. Players are penalised for using that bonus, as their stats won't go up while it's in effect. The update callback is only called when a counted drop is encountered though. Non-counted drops should be auto-smelted as well.

I've come up with a new plan though, one that makes use of the implementation details of minestats. minestats holds off on overriding the drop handler to account for mods such as creative that override it without ever calling the original version. minequest, or maybe one of the mods from the Minequest Modpack, can grab the original function, squirl it away for later use, and replace it with a dummy function for minestats to call. After minestats has replaced the function, this other mod can grab the minestats version, then replace the function with a version that calls the minestats version first, then does what needs to be done, and finally calls the original version. It all sounds convoluted, but it's not as bad as it seems. I hope. As I don't see a clear way this bug can actually be beneficial, I've fixed it. It is a bug after all, even though I only found it because I was trying to implement something similar in effect as a feature.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Errands and rest

Day 01130: Tuesday, 2018 April 10

Minetest log

Implementing the plan from yesterday took almost no effort at all. The description of the process may have made it seem convoluted, but was in fact just as straightforward as I'd hoped it'd be. I wasn't really up for programming anything else though. I guess I needed to rest my mind today. I ended up spending much of the day outside biking; getting some exercise and catching some rays.

Credit card

I got a credit card offer in the mail yesterday. If I spend five hundred dollars on it in three months, I get one hundred fifty back. It couldn't have come at much better a time. The fact is that I still need a backup laptop, and I still don't have a way to get a used on I know will work. As I said before, I'm going to need to get one new, but I've been putting that off. I've been saving up though, so now's a good time to get one. Hopefully I can find one cheaper than that, though I probably can't. Even if I can, a good chunk of the spend target will still be hit with the laptop purchase alone. I've also been considering getting a cheap camera; even the least expensive one I could find was forty dollars. Then there's groceries. I do like to eat.

The website was programmed in a very annoying way though; it was poorly programmed, to say the least. It kept deleting the previous of my Social Security number when I'd try to enter the next part, then complain that the part that remained wasn't a full Social Security number. I finally found a way to trick it into letting me enter the full number, which got it to stop complaining, but if I were a normal user and not a somewhat-geeky user, I'd've stood no chance of making the form work. Then, of course, the form refused to accept the fact that I have no telephone service. I had to give up last night, planning to go apply in person. It did accept my email address though, which would be interesting today.

My understanding is that the bankers weren't in yet when I arrived at the bank; only the tellers were there. I ended up needing to wait twenty minutes, so I spent ten of that walking around the parking lot a bit, and then it turned out the banker wasn't ready for my appointment and I waited another ten. It's a good thing I was in no particular rush today. The banker was nice, but was surprised I didn't have telephone service. Just like everyone else is surprised. I mean, everyone's subscribed to three different telephone lines these days, right? Their home phone, their mobile line, and ... their work mobile line? Something like that. Their computer system bugged out a few times; I blame Windows for that. Their system was also programmed to reject the st TLD I use for my email address; unlike the website. They changed it to a come to bypass the issue, then edited it after my profile was set up to use the correct TLD. A lot of the email address syntax checkers are poorly written and don't check for the things they really should, instead checking for irrelevant details that only usually apply, but it's even stranger that these checkers are inconsistently used. It really shows how stupid the programmers setting up the system are. Anyway, I was approved for the card, but it'll take time to arrive via post.

I later received an email from the banker telling me how much they care and want to make sure things go well; and to give them a ring if I need anything. Clearly they don't care about me enough to even remember that I don't have telephone service and can't call them. Not that I expect them to care, but I'm in a unique position to notice many of the times businesspeople lie to me as a client about their level of caring. They probably do care about the account though, even if not me. It's their job to care about my account.

Lucky ending digit drawing

This week's ending digit was four. And I still haven't taken the time to compile my findings and see if there's a ten-week cycle going on with the weekly drawing.

Drudgery

I swear, this school is so disorganised. They kept writing to me complaining that I hadn't made my payment yet, even though the post office said the payment should've made it to them ages ago. It was only on the final due date that they seem to have found and processed the payment. After they'd spent weeks scaring me, telling me they'd drop me from next term for lack of payment this term. Now today, they sent notification that I'd been approved for one of the courses I've applied to take next term. No mention was made for the other course. I waited five hours. (Part of this time was spent running the aforementioned errands.) These letters always come together though, and only one was sent this time. And the school always waits until the last minute to approve any course registrations; I mean, school starts *tomorrow*! I finally wrote to them asking about it, and instead of getting a response, I got the other course registration acceptance notification. I'm not sure what they were doing before, but alerting them to the issue got them to fix the symptom. The underlying problem is no doubt still there though. The school is a mess.

Bike lock receipt

I've been neglecting to take the new bike lock out of its packaging and start using it, but I wanted to hit the Cornbread Cafe between terms, and today was my last chance to do so. I opened the tin I'd stashed the broken lock in, and in which I'd put the new lock before leaving the bike shop, and I found the receipt for it in there. I was *certain* I'd left the receipt at the bike shop when claiming the warrantee, but I guess I was mistaken. I still have it in case there's need for a future claim after all.

Ranch dressing

I've managed to find vegan ranch dressing online, but never in stores. I asked one of the people at the cafe if they'd be able to tell me where the cafe gets theirs, but it turns out they make it in-house. They also told me it's not to hard to make though, and told me to mix almond milk, vegan mayonnaise, onion powder, and garlic powder. I checked out some recipes online too, and they say about the same thing, but with parsley added. One recipe adds dill as well. I guess I'll try making my own soon, since it doesn't seem to be even remotely difficult. I've never liked mayonnaise, so when I went vegan, I didn't even try vegan mayonnaise. This should be an interesting experiment, though I might wait until the credit card arrives to buy the supplies.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.